Sunil Kumar

sunilkumarsheoran@gmail.com +91-8130415105 LinkedIn Profile: Sunil Kumar 1106/1, Dayanand Colony, Model town, Karnal (Haryana), India. Pin: 132001

I am a software developer with more then 2-year experience with the companies <u>Drishti-soft Solutions</u> and <u>Morphing Machines</u>. I have worked on stand-alone product development projects along with projects in a team for high priority customer. Many time these feature or product required understanding customer requirement directly from Customer end.

Education

MAY 2014

B. Tech. of Information Technology / NIT Durgapur, West Bengal.

8.10 CGPA / Projects: Collage Study Point Website, Project on Data Structure, Digital Clock on Multisim and Exploration bot.

MARCH 2010

12th CBSE / K V Bengdubi, West Bengal.

85.8 % / Projects: Book Shop Management, Tic Tac Toe bot.

MARCH 2008

10th CBSE / K V Bengdubi, West Bengal.

79.8 %

Experience

JUNE 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2016

Software Developer / Drishti-Soft Solutions, Gurugram

- <u>Ameyo Report</u> (<u>GWT</u> based front-end and <u>Jasper</u> based backend). <u>UI Renew</u>, transformer (de-normalize data for reporting) modeling to ease generation of new transformers and backend enhancements. Shell Scripts for migration and debugging.
- Report Scheduler (Quartz library), Support for Centralized Reporting (Ameyo ART), Graphical Reports.
- I increased company's database performance for large scale customer's database (<u>PostgreSQL</u>) by 80-90% using <u>table partition</u>, Multicolumn Indexes, PostgreSQL Function and triggers.
- I increased the company's server-side stats manager's performance with cache (SoftHashMap) for reflective calls by 60%.
- Report Designer: Front-end GWT UI with generated data based on Model instances (.xmi) and later produces Model (EMF) object (.drxml) which converted by backend into jasper based object (.jrxml).
- L4 Critical Cases which were spread across multiple plugins of Ameyo Server and Client.
- Magic Numbers: Predict Hardware requirements (CPU, RAM and HDD) based on Customer requirements for reporting server.
- Automate HDFC collection process. Fresh UI, Integrating HCP for storage, SSO Authenticating server & Centralized Exclusion.
- Explorations: GWT bootstrap, Database Partition, HCP Integration, Bonita BPM.
- Awarded with Excellence Award 2016 and won /tmp 2014, also participated /tmp 2015 and HUNKAAR 2016. (10 days 24x7 coding event).
- Part of Hiring team for the 2016 and 2017 batches. (Question preparation, Interview Rounds and training after hiring)

JUNE 2013 - AUGUST 2013

Software Developer Intern / Morphing Machines, Bangalore.

- I designed and developed the front-end interface for a project called 'Development Of A Flexible Framework for A Network On Chip'.
- UI starts with a 4 page Wizard then shows <u>EMF</u> based resulted graph using <u>Graphiti</u> and finally produce a XML for the python written scripts which run and produce <u>VHDL</u> based back-end <u>NOC</u>.

Technical Tools

- Proficient: Eclipse, Java, PostgreSQL, GWT, JDBC.
- Intermediate: Groovy, JavaScript, C, C++, Python, HTML, CSS, REST, XML, JSON, Git, GitHub, Vim, Unix/Linux, Graphite, MVC, Adobe Photoshop.
- Familiar: PHP, Embedded C, AWS.

Activities

During College:

- Attended Workshops:
 - Ethical hacking & Information security by Kyrion Digital Securities 2010. (In 1st year).
 - Photoshop workshop. (In 1st year).
 - Android workshop. (In 2nd year)
- Participated in contests:
 - > 1st position in behind the Scene in MuKTi '13. (coding event).
 - → 1st position in InCanity in MuKTi '13. (coding event).
 - > 2nd Position in Simplex in ANK '12. (coding event).
 - Participated in National Robotic Contest 2013 Pune-India.

During School:

- 82% Marks secured in Junior NTSC Mathematics. (Jan 2005)
- MERIT in First Nationwide Biotechnology Olympiad
 - All India/state/school Ranks: 696/11/2 (Aug 2006)
- Distinction in International Assessments for Indian Schools Science.
 - ➤ In Top 4%.
- Distinction in International Assessments for Indian Schools Math.
 - ➤ In Top 5%.
- Participated in NSE in Astronomy 2008-2009 (Senior Level)
 - > Among top 10%
- Ranked among the 1.9% of all student appeared in AIEEE-2010.

Extracurricular activities:

- Selected for 35th ,36th ,37th K.V. National Sports meet after getting 3rd, 1st and 2nd position in Regional Sports meet in 2007,2006 and 2005 respectively (Game: CHESS).
- Participated 3 time in 8-10 Days High Altitude Trekking Programme (Manali, Shimla) and coved 110 K.M. and gained 12000 feet height.

Hobbies

Computer Gaming, Solving Programming Problems, Watching Movies & TV Shows, listening to music, Playing Chess & Football.